我新编了一个科学笑话  想听吗
I've invented a science joke, would you like to hear it?
好啊
Sure.
换一个灯泡要多少个爱迪生呢
How many Edisons does it take to screw in a light bulb?
几个
How many?
谁管他  他偷了灯泡这个创意
Who cares? He stole the idea
他不配有自己为主题的笑话
and doesn't deserve his own joke.
这是真的吗
Is that really true?
当然  所以你才能知道这是个好笑话
Of course, that's how you know it's a good joke.
好笑话就是得寓教于乐
It not only entertains, it informs.
抱歉打扰了
Hey, sorry to interrupt.
巴里
Uh, Barry,
换一个灯泡要多少个爱迪生呢
uh, how many Edisons does it take to screw in a light bulb?
你知道灯泡实际上不是爱迪生发明的吧
Did you know Edison didn't actually invent the light bulb?
你来干嘛  巴里
What do you want, Barry?
来给艾米送一份小小谢礼
Just wanted to drop this off as a little thank you for Amy.
为什么送我礼物
What's this for?
你的点子真的帮了我大忙
Your idea really helped me out.
我光锥量子化的论文已经发表到网上了
My light-cone quantization paper's online already.
反响非常棒
The response has been amazing.
那太好了
Well, that's fascinating.
我迫不及待要去拜读了
I can't wait to read it.
我也是呢
Oh, no, me as well.
请发到我电子邮箱sheldon@bazinga.biz
Uh, please e-mail it to sheldon@bazinga.biz.
为什么是.biz[商]吗
Why "Dot-biz"?
因为我一招"商"得你体无完肤
Because I just gave you the business.
还因为bazinga.com被人先注册了
And also bazinga.com was taken.
好啦  再次谢谢你
Anyway, thanks again.
库伯  去"吃鸡..."蛋吧
Cooper, suck eggs.
你什么时候去帮巴里·克里普奇了
Since when do you help out Barry Kripke?
我最近在思考通过元胞自动机来
Well, I'd been thinking about a cellular automata approach
研究神经元连接
to neuronal connectivity,
然后我觉得这可能对弦理论研究
and I thought it might have some interesting applications
有些不错的用途  小忙不值得一提啦
to string theory-- it's not a big deal.
是吗
Oh, really?
我研究弦理论走进死胡同那会儿
When I was doing string theory and hit a dead end,
你怎么没想过来帮我呢
why didn't you try to help me?
我有啊  你说生物学家唯一懂的数学
I did-- you said the only math biologists know is
就是如果有三只青蛙  一只跳走了
if you have three frogs and one hops away,
那还剩下两只
that leaves two frogs.
还挺有哏的  的确像是我会说的话
That's pretty funny, that does sound like me.
但这也不代表
But that doesn't mean
你就可以去站街边
that you should be standing on street corners
随便男人经过  就把你的计算给人家啊
handing out your math to whatever guy comes along.
谢尔顿  我们都是科学家
Sheldon, we're all scientists.
我就是帮忙一个同事
I helped out a fellow colleague.
你要不要这么小气
You're being petty.
我小气吗
I'm being petty?
你明知道我跟巴里是职场上宿敌
You know Barry and I have a professional rivalry.
你也听到他说的了  他叫我去"吃鸡..."蛋
You heard him-- he told me to suck eggs.
如果我跟他是朋友  那他就会叫我去
If we were friends, he would have suggested
吃些比较令人爽快的东西
I suck something more pleasant.
你笑什么
Why are you laughing?
你是不是学坏了
Did you learn something?
好的  妈
Okay, Ma.
替我跟格莱蒂斯阿姨问好
Say hi to Aunt Gladys.
我也爱你
Yeah, I love you, too.
再见
Bye.
你妈妈在佛罗里达玩得开心吗
Your mom having fun in Florida?
她很喜欢那里
Mmm, she loves it.
她终于找到个春暖花开  大家都在讨论
She finally found a place where everyone talks about
流了多少汗的地方
how sweaty they are.
总之  她是想我们回她家
Anyway, she wants us to go to the house
去看看斯图尔特会不会太"孤单"
and check in on Stuart because he might be "lonely."
她只是人很好嘛
She's just being nice.
我是他宝贝儿子  她怎么就不找人
Well, I'm her son, how come she doesn't send someone
来看看我孤不孤单
to check on me if I'm lonely?
因为你有个老婆
Because you have a wife.
是没错  可是有时候你下班好晚
Yeah, well, sometimes you work late.
我知道你不喜欢斯图尔特赖在你家
I know you don't like Stuart being in the house,
但他的店马上要重新开张了
but the store's about to reopen,
我相信他很快又能自食其力
I'm sure he'll get back on his feet.
那就太好了
That would be great.
我也非常想跟我妈的关系回到正常
I'd love for things between me and Mom to get back to normal.
"正常"这词有点言过其实  但你说是就是吧
Well, normal's a strong word, but sure.
-好啊  -好...
- Hey. - Hello.
你还好吧
You okay?
如果我还好  我会说  "好!"
If I was okay, I would've said "Hello"
而不是语气很衰的"好..."
and not the much more ominous "Hello."
怎么啦
What's going on?
我在生艾米的气
I'm mad at Amy.
她也在你最爱的无袖背心腋下留下汗渍了吗
Did she leave pit stains in your favorite crop top, too?
没有
No.
她帮巴里·克里普奇在线理论上做出突破
She helped Barry Kripke make an advancement in string theory.
听起来挺好的啊
Oh, that sounds like a good thing.
照理来说是  可是我已经不研究弦理论了
Well, it would be, except that I left string theory
因为我觉得那是条死路
because I decided it was a dead end.
而她背着我
Yeah, and then she went behind my back
跑去帮忙别人证明我错了
to help someone else prove me wrong.
而且还是帮我的宿敌
My rival, no less.
抱歉让你看到了这一幕
I'm sorry you had to see that.
我只遗憾我手边没相机
I'm sorry I didn't have a camera.
她为什么要这么对我呢
Why would she do this to me?
我想她不是故意要惹你生气
Well, I'm sure she didn't upset you on purpose.
而且你不是总说
Besides, aren't you the one who says
没有什么是比让科学进步更重要的吗
there's nothing more important than the advancement of science?
我说的是  没有什么比
No, I said there's nothing more important
"我"让科学进步更重要的
than me advancing science.
好吧  如果我没理解错
All right, well, if I'm understanding this right,
而她也真的只是帮忙了别的科学家
and all she did was help out another scientist,
我觉得你对这件事应该就算了吧
I'm thinking you might have to let this one go.
"算了吧"
Ugh, "Let it go."
这句话我听了一辈子了
I have heard that my whole life.
每次我有事情不开心  就有人让我"算了吧"
Every time something upsets me somebody says, "Let it go,"
说得好像都是我的问题
you know, like it's my fault,
我有不高兴的情绪是不对的
and it's not okay to feel the way I feel.
我不知道该说什么了
I don't know what to tell you.
你何不跟她谈谈呢
I mean, why don't you talk to her?
你就这点能耐吗
Is that all you have?
"跟她谈"和"算了吧"这种陈腔滥调的方法招数
Shopworn tidbits like "talk to her" and "let it go"?
佩妮  生活给了我又酸又苦的柠檬
Gee, Penny, life's giving me lemons.
我该怎么办
What should I do?
你可以找个"地方"塞进去呀
Well, you could shove them somewhere.
好吧  现在你会发散思维了
Okay, now you're getting creative.
再次感谢你们来帮忙
Thanks again for your help.
-不用谢  -别客气
- No problem. - Our pleasure.
这地方看起来真棒
The place really looks great.
是啊  你应该早几年放火烧掉的
Yeah, you should have burned it down years ago.
我再三地告诉你们  不是我故意烧掉的
I keep telling you I didn't burn it down.
我们知道  因为为了骗保险金
We know, we know-- because burning something down
而故意纵火  那叫"犯罪"
for the insurance money is a "crime."
斯尔图特  这地方简直焕然一新呀
Stuart, this place looks amazing.
谢谢
Thanks.
看得出来你很用心
You really did a nice job.
谢谢你在这整段过程中
And thank you for putting up with me
容忍我住在你妈家里
staying at your mom's through all this.
否则我也不能重开这家店
I-I couldn't have done it otherwise.
别说客套话了  我很高兴你能...
I appreciate that, and I'm glad you were able to...
那是我妈的家具吗
Is that my mother's furniture?
是啊  她说我可以搬过来用
Yeah, she said I could use it.
看起来很搭吧
Doesn't it look great?
还是放小房间里比较搭  因为它只属于那里
Not as great as it looks in the den where it belongs.
华仔
Howie.
你何不索性把整个房间都搬空算了
Why don't you just clean out the whole room?
把我三年级给我妈做的手工彩线小丑拿走啊
Take the string art clown I made her in third grade
再随便把我参加游泳班
and the ribbon I got in swim class
在水里憋气赢来的缎带奖拿走啊
for putting my face in the water.
你干嘛生气啊
What is your problem?
你妈都不介意了
She said it was okay.
我是她的儿子  我很介意
Well, I'm her son, and I say it's not okay.
哪门子的儿子  那手工小丑你也就花了十分钟做的吧
Some son-- looks like you spent ten minutes on that clown art.
或许我应该像你一样去念名牌艺术学校
Well, maybe I should've gone to a fancy art school like you.
然后开一家失败的漫画店
Then I could run a failed comic shop
店倒了就去骗其他人妈妈的钱
and mooch off some guy's mother.
我们先走吧  让你冷静一下
Why don't we leave so you can cool off?
这主意不错
I think that's a good idea.
快带他离开我的店
Take him out of my store.
你的店
Your store?!
你重开店的钱还是我妈给的
My mother gave you the money to reopen.
我哪儿也不去
I'm not going anywhere.
要不我们去给派对买点吃的吧
Why don't we go get the food for the party.
麻烦你们了
Thank you.
聪明  这样看起来我们好像在帮忙
Smart-- looks like we're being helpful.
其实我们只是想快点逃离这个难堪的场面
Mmm, when really we're just exiting an uncomfortable situation.
为什么偏偏要帮巴里·克里普奇呢
Kripke, you know, of all the people-- Barry Kripke.
我超....你是故意像个疯子一样叠衣服
I'm so... Are you folding it like a crazy person
好让我看不过眼帮你吗
to get me to do it for you?!
不是啊
No.
算了  我来吧
Oh, give me that.
我很好奇
Just out of curiosity,
如果我想放下某件事
if I were to let something go,
我该怎么做到呢
how would I do that?
我不知道  想想其他事情试试
I don't know-- just think about something else.
我可以想食蚁兽吗
Can I think about the spiny anteater?
可以啊
Sure.
食蚁兽
The spiny anteater...
从来没背着我去帮忙巴里·克里普奇
never went behind my back and worked with Barry Kripke.
这招一点用都没有
That didn't help at all.
有些人会尝试运用观想术
You know, some people try visualization.
那要怎么做
How does that work?
好
Okay,
想象你的问题是一支笔
imagine your problems are a pen.
好的
Okay.
现在想象你握着那支笔
Now imagine you're holding that pen.
好的
Okay.
现在松开手  让笔掉下来[算了吧]
Now open your hand and let it go.
可我才拿到这支笔
But I just got this pen.
上面有我名字的首字母缩写呢
It's got my initials on it and everything.
你看
Look.
谢尔顿  这没有那么难
Sheldon, this isn't that hard.
我或许有个让你教我的更好办法
I may have a better way that you can teach me.
怎么做
How?
如果我告诉你  在过去几个月里
What if I told you that over the past few months
艾米在暗中悄悄让你做一些智力小难题
Amy has secretly been giving you little puzzles
就为了对比你和她实验室黑猩猩谁更聪明
to test your intelligence against chimpanzees in her lab?
什么  她才没让我解决什么小难题呢
What? She didn't give me any puzzles.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
天啊  我把剪刀弄成两半装不回来了
Boy, I just can't seem to get these scissors back together.
你能帮个忙吗
Can you do it?
糟糕
Darn it.
我的眼睛进东西了
There's something in my eye,
我得把这些硬币按大小分类
and I need to sort these coins by size.
你能帮个忙吗
Can you help?
佩妮
Penny?
我超级想吃香蕉
I really want to eat this banana,
但它被卡在这个竹子机关箱了
but it's stuck inside this bamboo puzzle box.
那个科学婊
Son of a bitch!
太好了
Okay, that's great.
现在想  算了吧
Now, let it go.
你们居然把我和黑猩猩拿来做测试对比
I can't believe you were testing me against a chimp!
抱歉  测试你的人是艾米
Well, excuse me, Amy was testing you.
我可是很看好你哦
I was rooting for you.
对了  打开机关箱那次做得很不错哟
Good job on that banana box, by the way.
她为什么要这样做
Why would she even do this?
艾米在对人猿进行一系列实验
She's been conducting an experiment on apes
给它们各种难题  让它们解决
where they're given various puzzles to solve.
我对难题的复杂度表示惊讶
I was surprised at the complexity of the puzzles
觉得可能有些人类都未必能解决
and thought some humans wouldn't be able to solve them.
于是艾米就说  "想让实验变得更有趣吗"
That's when Amy said, "Want to make this interesting?"
"让实验变得有趣"
"Make this interesting"?
你们还拿我开赌盘了吗
You bet money on me?
当然不
No, no.
我们设计了让你参与其中的实验
We designed an experiment involving you.
瞧  这样是不是很有趣呀
See? Now, isn't that interesting?
这一点都不有趣
It's not interesting.
简直太侮辱人了
It's incredibly insulting.
好吧  或许这样会有用
Okay, maybe this will help--
想象你拿着一支笔
imagine you're holding a pen.
别想太多  就是一支普通的笔
Before you go too far, not a special pen
上面没有刻你的姓名首字母
with your initials engraved on it--
不然下一步会很难做
that'll make the next part really hard.
够了
That's it.
出去
Get out!
我不懂你为啥要冲我发火
I don't understand why you're mad at me.
你应该朝艾米发火
You should be mad at Amy.
跟我下午的时候一样
Like I was this afternoon.
你瞧  我已经算了
Hey, look at that-- I let it go.
出去
Get out!
-佩妮  -干嘛
- Penny? - What?
我好像把笔留在里面了
I think I left my pen in there.
我懂你为什么不开心
I understand why you're upset,
可是他真的很努力地准备开店
but he worked really hard to get the store ready.
不过是一些家具
And it's just furniture.
是我妈的家具
It's my mom's furniture.
属于我从小长大的房子
It belongs in the house I grew up in--
就放在那堆电视节目表旁边
next to that pile of TV Guides
在一个十岁孩子的眼里
and in plain view of what, for a ten-year-old,
可是很棒的线条艺术
was a quality piece of string art!
华仔  等漫画店成功
Howie, if the store succeeds,
斯图尔特有了收入
Stuart has a source of income,
他就能搬出你妈的房子
and he can move out of your mother's house.
付出这些旧家具作为代价
Seems like some old furniture is a reasonable price
还是挺划算的
to pay for that.
这倒是个好理由
That is a good point.
可是我跟你结婚不是为了好理由
But I didn't marry you for good points.
我跟你结婚是为了
I married you to blindly support me
不管我有多荒谬  你都会盲目支持我
no matter how ridiculous I'm being!
所以我才改写了我们的结婚誓言啊
This is why I had to rewrite our wedding vows.
你好  我们来拿漫画中心订的餐
Hi, we're here to pick up an order for Comic Center.
好  让我查一下
Sure, let me go check on that.
我觉得那是内森·菲利安
Dude, I-I think that's Nathan Fillion.
真的是他
Oh yeah, look at that.
他正在挑掉番茄里的沙拉
And he's picking the tomatoes out of his salad
跟我一样
just like I do.
我一直觉得自己跟他有缘
I always did feel a connection with him.
我有个主意
Oh, I have got an idea.
我们不会去拍卖网站上卖他的番茄
We're not selling his tomatoes on eBay.
如果我们能让《萤火虫》里的雷诺兹船长
No, if we got Captain Reynolds from Firefly
去斯图尔特的店办签名会
to do a signing at Stuart's store,
那一定超棒
that would be amazing.
一定很棒
That would be great.
所以我们要过去搭话吗
So should we go talk to him?
我不知道
I don't know.
如果他态度不好  以后他演的剧
I mean, if he's not nice, it's gonna make it hard for me
-我就没法看了  -屁咧
- to watch him in anything again. - What?!
演琼恩·雪诺的是个混蛋
The-the guy who plays Jon Snow was a jerk.
我们还是在看《权利的游戏》啊
We still watch Game of Thrones.
他是混蛋是因为你追了他的尾
He was a jerk because you rear-ended him.
我注意力被分散了嘛
I was distracted.
一个守夜人的车上绑着皮划艇
It's weird seeing a member of the Night's Watch
确实很奇怪嘛
with a kayak strapped to his car.
来吧
Come on.
你好 抱歉
Hi, excuse me, s-s...
我们不想打扰您
I-I don't mean to bother you,
可我们真的非常喜欢《萤火虫》
but we're just really big fans of Firefly.
还有《恐怖博士》
A-And Dr. Horrible.
你们认错人了
Oh, uh, I think you made a mistake.
我不是演员
I'm not an actor.
别这么说
Don't say that.
虽然没到朱迪·丹奇女爵士的等级
I mean, you're not Dame Judi Dench,
但你也挺不错的
but you're pretty great.
我懂了  你们以为我是内森·菲利安
Oh, yeah, I get it-- you think I'm Nathan Fillion,
可我不是
but I'm not.
你们要是不介意  我想继续吃午饭了
So if you don't mind, I would just love to eat my lunch.
走吧
Come on.
很抱歉打扰您了
Sorry to bother you.
真不懂他脾气怎么这么差
Don't know why he's so grumpy.
上次有人误以为我演了《少年派》
I got mistaken for that guy in Life of Pi once,
我到现在还飘飘然呢
and I'm still floating.
谢尔顿  是我
Sheldon, it's me.
你好
Oh, hey.
你看到了吗
D-Did you see that?
我自己找出了开门的方法
I-I figured out how to open the door all by myself.
我是不是该在笼子里扔粪庆祝啊
Maybe I'll fling some feces around my cage to celebrate.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我知道你秘密拿我做实验
I know you've been giving me secret puzzle tests.
谢尔顿  开门
Sheldon, open the door.
我不能开
I can't.
我光着呢
I'm naked.
我刚看到你了
I just saw you.
等一下
Hang on.
现在开门
Open the door now.
把裤子穿上
Pull up your pants!
这没什么大不了的
It's not a big deal.
我本科的时候经常做这种实验
I run tests like this on undergrads all the time.
如果你在大学里填写一些问卷
If you fill out some paperwork at the university,
我可以给你五块钱
I can get you $5.
谁稀罕你的五块钱
I don't want $5.
我要的是尊严
I want my dignity.
那你到底要多少  十块吗
So what are we talking, like, ten bucks?
-谢谢  -谢谢
- Thank you. - Thanks.
-再次抱歉  -没关系
- Sorry again. - No problem.
你确定你不是他吗
A-Are you sure you're not him?
你可以告诉我们的
Uh, you can tell us.
我们是科学家  不是什么狂热粉
We're scientists, not crazy fanboys.
好吧
All right, fine.
我就是他
I'm him.
结果你自己一个人在熟食店吃饭吗
And you're eating alone at a deli.
我不信  你不是他
I don't buy it-- you're not him.
我就想安静地吃个午饭
I just wanted to eat my lunch in peace.
不过我确实是他
But I really am him.
多谢你们能成为我的粉丝
And thank you very much for being a fan.
你们要是想可以跟我合照
If you want, uh, let's take a picture.
-那太好了  -好啊
- That would be great. - Great.
-谢谢  -当然
- Yeah, thank you. - You bet.
等等
Wait, hang on.
如果你真的是内森·菲利安
If you're really Nathan Fillion,
《萤火虫》里关于你帽子那句台词是什么
what's the line from Firefly about your bonnet?
"以我美丽的花帽子起誓  我要了结了你"
"I swear by my pretty floral bonnet, I will end you."
没错  就是这句
That's it, that's the line.
不过...
Although...
我也知道台词  但我也不是内森·菲利安啊
I knew the line-- doesn't make me Nathan Fillion.
你到底想不想拍照了
Do you want the picture or not?
我想和内森·菲利安拍照
I want a picture with Nathan Fillion.
跟一个长的像内森·菲利安  但是要比
How about a picture with a guy who looks like Nathan Fillion
平时的内森·菲利安更暴走一点的人呢
but a little more annoyed than Nathan Fillion usually is?
你怎么说
What do you think?
放脸书上是够了
Eh, it's good enough for Facebook.
不敢相信他们居然那么做
I can't believe they did that.
我知道  太侮辱人了
I know-- it's so insulting.
有一次  他们还让我把香蕉
At one point, they had me figure out
从一个机关盒里拿出来
how to get a banana out of a puzzle box.
等等  谢尔顿也给过我香蕉盒
Wait, Sheldon gave me a banana in a box.
他也在测试我
He was testing me, too.
难以置信
Unbelievable.
而且黑猩猩怎么可能打开嘛
And how could a chimp even solve that?
根本不可能
That was impossible.
真的吗  你没拿出来吗
Really? You couldn't get it out?
谢谢
Thank you.
这商店太棒了
Wow, the store looks great.
你们对我俩都做测试了吗
So you guys were testing us both?
你们脑子有啥毛病啊
What is the matter with you?
他们的毛病就是
Eh, what's the matter with them is
他们觉得自己聪明到冒烟了
they think they're so smart they don't care
根本不在乎会伤到别人的感情
if they hurt other people's feelings.
-好像是这么回事  -完全不是这么回事
- Sounds like us. - That's not true.
我还是没理解你们为什么生气
I still don't understand why you're upset.
你们每道题都解的比黑猩猩快
You solved every puzzle faster than all of the chimps.
除了比巴纳巴斯慢  但他吃着药呢
Well, except Barnabas, but he was on Adderall.
对不起  可是逼得我快疯了
I'm sorry, but it's making me crazy.
你能不能就这么算了吧
Can you please just let it go?
这事我能帮忙
Oh, I can help you with that.
想象你手里握着一支普通的笔
Imagine you're holding an ordinary pen.
而你最喜欢地笔好好的放在口袋里
While your favorite pen is safe and secure in your pocket.
等会再说
Hold that thought.
你好
Hello?
要怎么才能弥补
How can I make this up to you?
答案就在这个机关盒里
The answer's in this puzzle box.
看看你能不能打开它呢
Let's see if you can open it.
你就不能先提醒他一下家具的事吗
You could have at least warned him about the furniture.
我们搬的时候  我就是这么说的
That's what I said when we moved it.
你还帮着搬了
You helped him?!
没有  抱枕都是斯图尔特自己搬的哦
No, Stuart picked out those throw pillows all on his own.
你没事吧
Hey, you okay?
有事
Uh, no.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我母亲去世了
My mom died.
什么
What?
是我姨妈打来的
That was my aunt.
妈妈小睡了一会
Ma took a nap.
但她再也没醒过来
She never woke up.
天啊  华仔
Oh, my God, Howie.
节哀
I'm so sorry.
我们能帮上什么吗
What can we do?
不知道
I don't know.
我能说句话吗
May I say something?
时机不对  谢尔顿
Not right now, Sheldon.
-但我觉得可以安慰到他  -兄弟
- But I think it would be comforting. - Buddy...
不  没事的
No, it's okay.
你想说什么
What?
当我的父亲去世时
When I lost my own father,
我没有任何朋友陪我渡过那段时间
I didn't have any friends to help me through it.
而你有
You do.
我真以为他会说"算了吧"
I really thought he was gonna say, "let it go."
谢谢  伯纳黛特
Okay, thanks, Bernadette.
一路平安
Travel safe.
好  再见
Okay, bye.
他们订了机票
They booked a flight.
现在往机场走呢
They're heading to the airport now.
霍华德状态怎么样
How's Howard holding up?
他还撑得住
He's hanging in there.
你还好吗  斯图尔特
How are you doing, Stuart?
还是不敢相信她居然走了
Still can't believe she's gone.
是这个女人收留了我
I mean, that woman took me in.
如果没有她  我可能要露宿街头了
If it wasn't for her, I-I would have been homeless.
我们中也肯定有人会收留你的
One of us would have taken you in.
是吗  我怎么没想起来有谁说过
Yeah, I don't recall any offers.
但这样也挺好  我很高兴最后是她收留了我
But, you know, uh, I-I'm glad it worked out the way it did
因为我由此认识了一位善良的人
because I got to know this wonderful person.
是啊
Yeah.
沃罗威茨夫人非常特别
Mrs. Wolowitz was pretty special.
当我刚搬到美国
When I first moved to America,
那时霍华德是我唯一的朋友
Howard was my only friend.
她让我在她家时宾至如归
She made me feel so welcome in her home.
不过事出有因  因为那几年
Which says a lot, because, those first few years,
她一直以为我是她家园丁
she thought I was the gardener.
她每次见到我
Whenever I saw her,
都说我太瘦了  使劲让我多吃
she'd say I was too skinny and try and feed me.
她也是这样对我的
She did that to me, too.
别抢走我对她的独家回忆
Don't take this away from me.
我不介意她的大吼大叫
I didn't care for her yelling.
但现在我再也听不到了
But now that I'm not going to hear it again,
真伤心
I'm sad.
你要是乐意  之后我可以吼你
If you want, I can yell at you later.
你吼不出她的霸气
It won't be as good.
我们举杯
Let's have a toast.
敬沃罗威茨夫人
To Mrs. Wolowitz.
我们所有人亲爱的...
A loving mother...
母亲
...to all of us.
我们会想念您
We'll miss you.